LAKSHAY BHATIA

ASSISTANT SYSTEMS ENGINEER, TCS (DELHI)

WORK EXPERIENCE

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

Assistant Systems Engneer | Gurugram, India | May 2021 - Present

Working as a **Full stack web developer** and was involved in developing and maintaining several APIs and **Azure cloud based services** for a Manufacturing business domain based web application.

- Working with C#, Microsoft NET Core framework for developing web APIs services
- In front end side currently involved in creating UIs screens on React JS
- Used various Azure Cloud services including Active Directory , Azure Functions, Logic Apps and Azure Devops .

CLOUDIFY

Software Developer Intern | BrøNdby, Denmark (Remote) | Jan 2021 - May 2021

Worked as Business Process Automation Developer where I was involved in developing automation APIs using NodeJS and serverless cloud functions (Autocode), designing automation logics using several SaaS services for example pipedrive CRM, Hubspot CRM

- Used several Automation tools like Zapier, Integromat for automating several SaaS with some set of Actions and triggers.
- Used NodeJS, Javascript for creating Automation scrips and utilized serverless function cloud service to develop the business logic -Autocode.

IMMANENT SOLUTIONS

Software Developer Intern | Mohali, Punjab, India | Sept 2020 - Dec 2020

Worked as a **Full stack web developer**. Worked on several technologies on different projects that involves - **React, React Native, NodeJS**

- Worked on a Mobile Application project that involves creating several screens for the app using **React Native**.
- Worked on Backend Project that involved developing several APIs for Web App using NodeJS and MySQL database.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Awarded as TCS Star of the Month Award for a customer Project in the month of December 2021.

SUMMARY

Accomplished software developer with more than 1 years of work experience with excellent computer programming skills. Specialized in developing Backend, Frontend and cloud based applications as well as designing computer applications. Possessing excellent communication and interpersonal skills. Ability to work under pressure.

SKILLS

C# , .NET Core		
Javascript		
ReactJS	_	
NodeJS		
HTML, CSS		

EDUCATION

MSc Electronics

Jamia Millia Islamia University, New Delhi

Jul 2018 - Jul 2020 8.85 CGPA

BSc Hons Instrumentation

Bhaskaracharya College Of Applied Sciences, Delhi University, New Delhi Jul 2015 - Jul 2018 7.959 CGPA

LANGUAGES

PROJECTS

INSTAGRAM CLONE

Instgram clone is a react App , I have both front-end and backend created using React Js, Node Js, Mongo DB and used Context API for state management.

• Project Link: github.com/LAKSHAY-BHATIA/instagram-clone-fullstack

YOUTUBE CLONE APP

Youtube Clone App is a clone app of youtube made with react native and react redux. It is capable of running on both Android and IOS mobile platforms. Google API integrated in the App as backend.

• **Project Link**: github.com/LAKSHAY-BHATIA/youtubee-clone-react-native-app

IOT VOICE CONTROLLED HOME AUTOMATION

Devolped a Home automation project which was used to control various Electrical appliances. Devices were controlled with an App or through voice assistants like Google Assistant or Amazon Alexa

• Project Link: github.com/LAKSHAY-BHATIA/voice-controlled-home-automation-

OCR WITH SPEECH CONVERTOR

OCR with Speech Convertor is a reading assistance device for visually impaired which is based on raspberry pi with a camera module and used cloud computing to convert image to text and text to speech.

• Project Link: www.youtube.com/watch?v=cyPN54Va5FQ&t=68s

English

Hindi

HOBBIES







PERSONAL DETAILS

Gender

Male

Marital Status

Single

Nationality

Indian